Hey, are you listening to me?
I told you!
The auto-locking door
was left hanging wide open!
Don't make me repeat myself!
I already reported
this last week too!
Why am I paying such
high management fees
for such crappy service?
Huh?
What?
Screw you, you'll do it today!
Come inspect it right now!
Are you even listening to me?
You're dead!
(opening theme music)
Taichi Kanada in
Morioka, in June.
Osamu Shimada in
Yokohama, in August.
Hiroshi Yamato in
Nagoya, in September.
All three died in
similar circumstances.
They were stabbed to
death by a cursed spirit
at the entrances
to their apartments.
And all three of them just
days prior to their murders
had filed the same complaint
with their property managers.
They all claimed they'd
found the security doors
left wide open.
"Episode 22: The Origin
of Blind Obedience"
None of the other residents
were able to provide
any other clues.
But none of these
dates or locations match.
Maybe it's not the
same cursed spirit?
Hey wait, what if the spirit
is messing with the doors?
Do cursed spirits trigger
those sensors, you think?
They don't show up
on cameras, right?
Apparently, the cursed spirit
made the door operating
mechanism go crazy,
not the sensors.
Ohhh.
Mechanisms?
Yeah. And as for whether
or not the same cursed spirit
was behind all three.
We couldn't make a decision
based on the residuals.
Too much time
had passed by then.
So, we looked for connections
between the three of them.
And we discovered that all three
had attended the same
middle school for two years.
Which would mean
that all three must have
received the same curse.
And it didn't activate
until years later?
Oh!
Precisely.
That's highly likely.
So that's why we're on our
way to their middle school now.
We'll be picking up a fourth
man who also went there
and knew all of the victims.
I'm assigning you
three as sorcerers
to see what you can
find out from him.
Way to go, Kugisaki!
Hah! No sweat.
(sighs)
"Spirit Lantern"
"Morishita Family Funeral 11:00"
[Itadori] A funeral?
Is this the home of
that acquaintance?
Yeah.
Or it used to be.
Well, this sucks.
Turns out he died the
same way the other three did.
He lived with his family, so
there was no auto-locking door,
but he was killed
right at the entrance,
just like the others.
And he'd also recently told
other family members that
another time he'd
come home alone,
he'd found that "the
door was unlocked,
"but it wouldn't open."
I asked his parents about
the other three victims,
but they said they didn't
know what relationship
he might've had with them.
Man, there goes our only lead!
Aagh, don't worry!
I'm sure we'll find something
at the middle school!
I sure hope so.
I've made you guys an
appointment with a teacher,
so I'm counting on you.
[Itadori] Roger that.
Oh? (snicker)
Hey, check out these two punks!
How about we kick their asses?
[Itadori] What for?
Hmm?
Huh?
Hmmm?
Uhh, it's good to see you again!
Well, look at that.
You're getting some respect.
An aura just pours out,
even if you try
your best to hide it.
[Student A] We haven't seen
you since graduation, Fushiguro!
Huh?
I uh went to school here.
Well that's a surprise
but that's not the point!
Explain yourself!
What'd you do?
What happened when
you were at this school?
Wait! Maybe we should
just ask these two!
Hey, Idiot A and Idiot B, just
what'd this guy do to you?
We both, along with
every other stoner
and slacker and delinquent
here at this school
got beat up by Fushiguro.
Huh?
Pretty much, yeah.
Why're you talking like a robot?
Would you look at me!
What is your deal?
What the hell's going
on here with you?
Hey you three!
Who are you?
Students from other schools
are not allowed in here!
Who're you to be
questioning us, huh?
He's clearly staff.
Take it down a notch.
We have permission
to visit today.
Hmm?
Ahh, the investigators?
How very young you all are!
Please keep your pass
visible for your entire stay here.
Oh!
Is that Fushiguro?
Hello.
[Both] He remembers you!
So this man has been
here for a long time then?
Probably.
Takeda was a
member of the staff.
Great, then I leave it to you!
How convenient.
Kanada, Shimada, Yamato
and now Morishita too, eh?
It's quite a shock
to hear about this.
But it must be
nearly 20 years now
since those boys graduated.
Still I remember it
like it was yesterday.
They were all
problem children too,
though not as bad as you.
What do you want to know?
Curious rumors, or dark rumors,
or connections to bad adults.
[Both] Hey, problem child!
Also anything of
ill omen, of course.
Dark rumors?
They could be difficult,
but it was just your
average middle school stuff.
Then again, ill omen?
Are you talking
about that old story?
The Yasohachi Bridge?
That one?
You're still here A and B?
What's the Yasohachi Bridge?
It's a suicide site.
Considered haunted
by some of the locals.
Oh yes you're right!
Back then it was all the
rage among delinquents
to bungee jump off
Yasohachi Bridge late at night
to test one's courage.
What a bunch of weirdos.
I'm surprised there are
people dumber than me!
What do you use for a cord?
No no, we don't bungee jump!
We just heard people
talking about it.
It's a thing from
back in the day.
One day Kanada
and the other three
all were absent
without permission.
By itself that wasn't strange.
Then, when we contacted
all of their families,
we learned that
none of the four boys
had come home from
school the day before.
It caused a pretty big stir.
Then they were found laying
under the bridge, unconscious.
They got chewed
out good as I recall.
But all four of them
swore up and down
that they didn't
remember a thing.
I think that's it.
As a matter of fact
I've been to that bridge.
To bungee jump?
Just like in schools,
curses can take root
in haunted locations.
So people from Jujutsu High
regularly patrol that bridge.
There wasn't anything
strange at the time.
Even though it
became a little famous,
it's still in use as
a normal bridge.
We still have to go
and check it out though.
I agree.
Fushiguro?
There's something I was
hoping to ask you about.
What is it?
When you were in school here
Tsukimi always took care of you.
Is she doing okay these days?
Yes.
Wait, who is Tsumiki?
My sister.
What?
How come you never tell
us anything about yourself?
Yeah, what she said!
When they find cursed
objects like these...
Why don't they
just destroy them?
They can't destroy them.
Not with the special-grades.
So they use a pact to
put their life on pause
to not harm others but
preserve their existence.
[Mahito] Sukuna's
fingers still cause harm.
That's an exception.
Sukuna's a monster
that will still attract curses,
even after it became
a cursed object
and was divided into 20 pieces.
So it can choose,
its own vessel.
Huh, well, then anyone will
work for this purpose, right?
(heaving breaths)
Hey listen...
Cash?
Cash!
Right? That's what
you want isn't it?
I can get it!
All you want!
So will this one work okay?
He still can't see me
even at this juncture.
His ability level is low.
Open up and say ahh!
(gagging)
(upbeat music)
"Jujutsu Kaisen"
(erie music)
(cars passing)
[Akari] We're here.
Koi no Kuchi Canyon,
Yasohachi Bridge.
Once you confirm a cursed
spirit is here, I'll lower a veil.
You got it!
(erie music)
Hey. Sorry to ask you
this when you just woke up.
But could you go run
a little errand for me?
(monster howl)
(yawning)
What a bust.
Not hide nor hair
of a cursed spirit.
We didn't sense any
presences or any residuals either.
I see.
I guess this isn't it.
We're back to square one.
Won't matters get
worse if we don't hurry?
[Nobara] Why?
Well it's a famous
haunted location, right?
So, there might still be plenty
of others who got cursed.
And right now, the death
rate's at a hundred percent.
We don't want to see
any others die, right?
[Nobara] Yeah, true.
Donngg!
Bungee jumping was
all the rage back then!
So maybe the act of
jumping off is the key?
Did she really just say "dong"?
Did I actually hear that?
She did, she did!
Doesn't matter, Itadori
already tried that.
Huh?
Aagh!
You didn't really jump with that
vinyl cord tied to you did you?
Gyaaah!
Agh!
Hey, there you are!
-Oh thank goodness!
-Hm?
Fushiguro!
Who's this guy?
He's that guy you
were making fun of.
I think you called
him "Idiot A".
Oh!
You were talking
about Yasohachi Bridge.
So I thought I
might find you here.
Fujinuma?
Hm?
A classmate.
My big sister
It's nice that you still
remember me, Fushiguro.
[Idiot A] I was talking to
my sister about you yesterday
and... uh...
Yes well, Morishita's funeral
was held in our neighborhood.
So then when my brother said
that you were looking into
him and also Yasohachi Bridge,
I thought maybe the
two things were related.
What two things?
[Fujinuma] Morishita's
unexpected death,
and Yasohachi Bridge.
No they're not.
No connection.
You see, I...
I went there too!
In eighth grade I went to
the bridge late one night!
Has anything out of the ordinary
happened at home recently?
Any strange feelings that
seem to only affect you
and no one else?
That's just it!
You see my family runs
a shop here in town.
And lately I've been finding
the shop's automatic door
wide open when I come home,
but it only happens to me!
Mom and Dad both told
me it's just a coincidence.
But there was definitely
something there!
It scared me.
And yesterday my brother
told me about you three
and I remembered that
night out at the bridge.
[Akari] When did the issue
with your automatic door start?
[Fujinuma] It's happened
about every other day
for exactly one week now.
So there's at least two weeks
between the time
when the four victims
first noticed something
wrong and the day they died.
We still have some time.
Wait, you didn't go
out to that bridge
all by yourself did you?
Do you remember
who you went with?
So then this really does
have something to do with--
No it's just about your door!
And it has nothing to
do with Morishita's death
or anyone else's!
Fushiguro and his friends here
are just helping me with
research for my college report:
"Electromagnetic Waves
from Haunted Locations
"and their Effects
on Electronic Stuff
Such a pain in the neck!
But I need to get reports
from all kinds of sources.
So I'd love to hear who was
with you out at the bridge.
After lying to her like
this we'd better save her
It was a test of courage for
three of us in the same club.
And in fact, Fushiguro,
your sister Tsumiki was
there with us that night.
Tsumiki?
Not his sister?
I see.
I'll ask Tsumiki what
she remembers about it.
Okay!
Then I guess I can just give
these two a ride back home now.
You three keep working
on the report until I get back.
There's something
going on here isn't there?
Well I can't very well let you
both go home on one bike!
Fushiguro.
Fushiguro!
Fushiguro, you've
gotta snap out of it.
You gotta make
sure that she's safe!
I'm alright.
Hang on, I just need a moment.
Yes, I understand.
You need guard
for Tsumiki, right?
I'll try, but as
far as sorcerers,
second-grades are
all that's available.
Second grade...
And, since the number of victims
there far exceeds our estimates,
we'll probably
have to re-evaluate
the curse's grade, as well.
And another thing.
You were probably
assigned this mission
with Itadori's growth
taken into account.
So if it's even more dangerous
than was originally thought,
then it might be too much
for a second-grade sorcerer.
It's just as dangerous
for all of you, as well.
Personally, I recommend
you withdraw.
What do I do?
Do I go back by
myself right now?
No, the mission was already
dangerous for all three of us.
I can't leave it to
just the two of them.
Gojo will return next week.
I could wait and ask him then...
No, I can't!
The time limit is
the big problem!
This isn't the type of cursed
spirit that attacks someone.
It's the type that activates
a cursed technique
from within a marked person.
So there's no point staying
nearby and protecting them!
I have to exorcise
it right away!
Why were you talking
to Ijichi just now?
About your sister?
Is she okay?
Yes she's fine.
But this mission's
danger level just shot up.
Other sorcerers will
be taking over the case.
You two can go home now.
Wait, why just us two?
Hey!
What about you?
I'll leave after I say
goodbye to Takeda.
Now just go!
(cellphone rings)
Hello, Nitta.
Thanks for your help.
There's something
I want to ask you.
[Nitta] About the
procedure, right?
Fujinuma didn't go over
the side of Yasohachi Bridge.
They held their test of
courage underneath the bridge.
Itadori went under it, too.
[Nitta] Most likely, you can't
get below it from up above.
The cursed spirit
is within its barrier,
so the procedure's important.
You go at night,
from underneath.
And one more thing...
It's impossible to
constantly keep a domain
imbued with a technique
deployed forever.
Which means it's
like that barrier
at the juvenile
detention center,
an incomplete domain.
I'm actually lucky
this time around.
Since I won't need a veil.
You really don't tell us
enough about yourself.
Sure don't.
If you didn't
notice us until now
you're seriously lost in space.
We're not saying you
have to tell us everything
but come on, at
least let us help.
We're friends, aren't we?
Tsumiki...
Is still bedridden.
(light gasps)
The curse of the
Yasohachi Bridge
only appears to its victims.
Since she can't
communicate herself.
I have no idea when
she'll be killed by the curse.
So I want to
exorcise it right away.
But now that our mission's
danger level increased...
Okay, okay!
Geez, we get it now.
You should have just told
us all of that from the start.
(pleased soft chuckle)
The cursed spirit
is within its barrier,
so the procedure's important.
You go at night,
from underneath.
And one more thing...
At the bottom of the
canyon there might be a river.
Crossing a river or other border
acts that symbolize
crossing over to the afterlife
these carry important
meanings in sorcery.
(monster chittering, warbling)
There it is.
I'm looking forward to this.
(monster warbling)
Huh?
What's this?
Someone beat me here?
Huh?
Fushiguro, this
one's different, huh?
Yeah.
Then why don't you two
focus on that first one.
I'll exorcise this one.
Is that so?
You're going to play
with me now, are you?
(ending theme music)
[Unison] Juju Stroll!
Help, stop that guy!
-He stole my purse!
-Huh?
Thanks!
This was so kind of you!
Allow me to treat
you to a free meal.
[Kugisaki] Oh we
couldn't accept that.
[Itadori] Of course we could!
Thank you! I'd love to eat!
This restaurant has
been in my family
for four generations now.
That was supposed to come
to an end with my father.
But I stayed.
I insisted on trying to
keep it up and running.
I just wanted to
keep the restaurant,
and our special
style of cooking alive.
[Both] Ahhh! What a nice story!
[Woman] Sorry for the
wait! Here's our pride and joy,
the gyoza meal passed
down for generations!
[Unison] Let's dig in!
Thank you for the meal!
So, guys.
Is it really gyoza
when there's no meat?
Basically just cabbage
and some thickener?
I'm so glad you said that!
Yeah, right!
And she was a really nice
woman and all that but come on!
But apparently, gyoza is
meant to be a vegetable dish,
not a meat dish.
[Unison] Seriously?
(upbeat instrumental music)
"Episode 23: The Origin
of Blind Obedience - 2 -"